<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>ChёrtART (technology)</title><link>http://chertart.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://chertart.com/categories/technology.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 23:08:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>nikola</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Van Gogh Alive</title><link>http://chertart.com/posts/van-gogh-alive/</link><description>&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.04.49.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.04.49.jpg" class="align-right" src="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.04.49.jpg" style="height: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.10.27.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.10.27.jpg" class="align-right" src="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.10.27.jpg" style="height: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exhibition «&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vangoghalive.ru/en"&gt;Van Gogh Alive&lt;/a&gt;» is held in Design Center Artplay. Exhibition was created by Australian company &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://grandeexhibitions.com/"&gt;Grande Exhibitions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entirely multimedia exhibition allows spectator to feel himself inside Van Goghs canvases. This feeling is achieve by quite big screens placed on the walls floor and columns. Dynamic images change with classic music. Everything would be alright but the organizers had not paid enough attention to the quality of the images, their resolution to be exact. Pixels were clearly visible, it wasn't pleasing for the eyes. Quite inaccurate installation of the projector gave ragged pixel edge on one of the central screens in the first hall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who were particularly impressed with the exhibition there was  a place to work with some easels and pencils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.12.49.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.12.49.jpg" src="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.12.49.jpg" style="height: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.30.52.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.30.52.jpg" src="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.30.52.jpg" style="height: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.13.39.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.13.39.jpg" src="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.13.39.jpg" style="height: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.33.46.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.33.46.jpg" src="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.33.46.jpg" style="height: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.19.20.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.19.20.jpg" src="http://chertart.com/images/van-gogh/2014-01-08-20.19.20.jpg" style="height: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;В центре дизайна Artplay проходит выставка «&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vangoghalive.ru/en"&gt;Van Gogh Alive&lt;/a&gt;». Выставка была подготовленна австралийской компанией &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://grandeexhibitions.com/"&gt;Grande Exhibitions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Полностью мультимедийная выставка дает возможность зрителю почувствовать себя внутри «оживших» полотен Ван Гога. Это ощущение достигается благодаря весьма большим экранам, размещенных на стенах, полу и колоннах. Динамические изображения сменяются под произведения классической музыки. И всё было бы великолепно, если бы организаторы уделили должное внимание качеству демонстируемых изображений, а именно их разрешению. Были отчетливо видны пиксели, которые никак не радовали взгляд. Также некоторая неточность в установке проектора дала пиксельную «ёлку» по краю одного из центральных экранов первого зала.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Для особо впечатлившихся выставкой было отведено место для творчества: несколько мольбертиков и карандаши.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>art</category><category>technology</category><category>modern art</category><category>van gogh alive</category><category>exhibition</category><guid>http://chertart.com/posts/van-gogh-alive/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 22:15:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New art forms in digital era</title><link>http://chertart.com/posts/new-art-forms-in-digital-era/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On the 3 of December First Russian Conference of Junior Researchers «Problems of modern humanitarian education through the eyes of youth» took place in Moscow State University of Design and Technology. I participated there with topic «New art forms in digital era».&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The XX century is considered as the beginning of the digital era. Development of computer technologies led to a rapid development of digital art. A lot of novel art directions arised: digital literature, digital painting, photo impressionism, ASCII-graphics, pixel art, chiptune, demoscene. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.google.com/culturalinstitute/project/art-project"&gt;Virtual museums&lt;/a&gt;, three-dimensional modeling and printing appeared. Art, physics, mathematics, programming and technologies are tightly interlaced with one another so it is very hard to distinguish them. Artist workplace is computer in increasing frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of powerful personal computers has led to the promotion professional programs for graphics and design. The widespread distribution of available mobile devices with cameras allowed not only to take pictures, but immediately impose them predefined effects. Previously artistic change of pictures was carried out only by complex systems of optical filters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human brain adapts to the growing flow of information. This happens in various ways. For example, the improving «efficiency» of remembering: for the modern person it is easier to remember not the information itself, but the way it was found. This process affects perception of art work features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artworks translation to digital form leads to multiple problems. Сhange in the perception of the viewer at several levels: on the level of form and scale perception, on the level of colors perception and at the level of whole work detalization should be noted especially. Therefore artists need more and more powerful ways for influencing feeling. Copyright problem is also important for modern artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is harder to find a masterpieces of human genius among the ocean of modern art objects. Most of them are only the reflection of technology, not an artistic images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some examples of modern intersection of art and technology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="425" height="344" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/toXNVbvFXyk?rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;iframe width="425" height="344" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/EXRt64HEBrk?rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><category>art</category><category>technology</category><category>msudt</category><category>conference</category><category>modern art</category><guid>http://chertart.com/posts/new-art-forms-in-digital-era/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 23:45:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>